Let's think for a moment why what we've come up with now is
下面看看为何现在的优化方式
superior to the way we were doing optimization before.
比之前的优化方式要好
Remember how before we had
之前我们使用一个
this large covariance matrix of assets that we were using to estimate portfolio variance.
很大的资产协方差矩阵估算投资组合方差
Well, now we have a smaller number of factors.
现在使用更少数量的因子
Common commercial risk models have around 70 factors.
常见的商业风险模型大约有 70 个因子
So, this matrix is now a 70 by 70 matrix,
所以这个矩阵是 70 x 70
as opposed to the potentially several thousand by
如果使用资产协方差矩阵的话
several thousand matrix we would have had if
则矩阵维度将是
we were using a covariance matrix of the assets.
几千 x 几千
There are literally just fewer elements in this matrix.
这个矩阵的元素少多了
This means that we have reduced the number of quantities we are trying to estimate.
我们减少了要估算的量
How many fewer elements are there?
到底是多少个元素呢？
Well, let's count them.
我们来数一数
Let's say the dimension of our asset covariance matrix is
假设资产协方差矩阵的维度是 n
n. Remember that covariance matrices are symmetric.
该协方差矩阵是对称的
There are n elements on the diagonal.
对角线上有 n 个元素
If we look at the remaining elements,
再看看非对角线上的元素
we see we have a matrix of dimension n minus 1 by
矩阵维度是 (n-1) x n
n. But each element is in this matrix exactly twice.
但是这个矩阵里的每个元素都出现了两次
So, the number of unique elements is n times n minus 1 divided by 2.
所以唯一元素的数量是 n*(n-1)/2
So, we have n elements along the diagonal and a half
对角线上有 n 个元素
of n times n minus 1 number of elements that are not along the diagonal.
非对角线上有 n*(n-1)/2 个元素
We'll rearrange the formula a bit to get n times n plus 1 all divided by 2.
调整下公式 变成 n*(n+1)/2
So, in total, we have n times n plus 1 divided by 2 quantities to estimate.
我们总共要估算 n*(n+1)/2 个量
Let's say n is 3,000.
假设 n 是 3,000
This is then around 4.5 million quantities.
这个约为 450 万个
If n is instead 70,
如果 n 是 70
then this is more like 2.5 thousand quantities.
这个约为 2500 个
There's a big difference in scale there.
差距还是很大的
There are many fewer opportunities to introduce estimation error.
出现估算误差的概率小多了
The fact that we are now estimating many fewer parameters is
现在要估算的参数少多了是一件好事
a good thing and an important reason why we use factor models of risk.
也是我们使用风险因子模型的重要原因
Another thing to remember is that each of the elements in this matrix is
还需要注意的是 这个矩阵中的每个元素
an estimate of variance or covariance of random variables.
都是随机变量的方差或协方差估值
In practice, we estimate variances and covariances using time series of data.
在实践中 我们使用时间序列估算方差和协方差
If you have n assets,
如果有 n 个资产
and you want to estimate the covariance matrix of those n assets,
并且需要估算这 n 个资产的协方差矩阵
then the number of days of return that you need,
那么所需的收益率天数 t
t, has to be greater than n,
必须大于 n
and ideally much greater than n. There's more we
理想情况下是比 n 大很多
need to talk about to explain why the number of data points needs
为何数据点的数量必须
to be much greater than the number of variables
比变量 n 的数量大很多还有很多要解释的地方
n. But one problem with insufficient data is
但是数据不足的一个问题是
that there won't be enough observations to accurately
没有足够的观察量来准确估算
estimate all of the variances and covariances,
所有的方差和协方差
which means that the covariance matrix,
导致基于样本的
based on the sample,
协方差矩阵
would be significantly different from the population covariance matrix.
可能与总体的协方差矩阵截然不同
Also, PCA, using such a covariance matrix,
此外 使用此类协方差矩阵的 PCA
would not be able to produce meaningful principal components.
无法生成有意义的主成分
If you have 3,000 securities,
如果有 3,000 个证券
you need at least 3,000 days of data,
需要至少 3,000 天的数据
which is about 12 years.
约为 12 年
But we also know that variance and covariance probably change over time.
但是我们知道随着时间的推移方差和协方差很可能会改变
So, does using 12 years of data to
所以使用 12 年的数据
predict the variance for the next month even make sense?
预测下个月的方差有意义吗？
Another reason people use
人们使用风险因子模型
the risk factor model formulation of
构建协方差矩阵的另一个原因
the covariance matrix is that you get around that problem.
就是能避免这一问题
N is a smaller number,
n 是很小的数字
and so t can be a smaller number.
所以 t 也可以是很小的数字